（伊月(いづき)）うっ…
（木吉(きよし)）あっ…
（火神(かがみ)）なっ…
（日向(ひゅうが)）あっ…
No way!
（リコ）うそ！？
（黒子(くろこ)）はっ…
Imayoshi's on Kuroko?!
（リコ）今吉(いまよし)が黒子君のマーク！？
Did you know?
（今吉）知っとるか？
鏡越しにしか—
Some things can only be seen from behind the mirror.
見えへんもんも
あるらしいで
（今吉）ううっ！
（伊月）あっ… スリー！？
A three!
Hyuga!
日向！
I'll return the favor.
（日向）お返しだ！ くらえっ！
Take this!
（桜井(さくらい)）ええい
（日向）ああっ…
The Barrier Jumper!
（土田(つちだ)）バリアジャンパーが！
（小金井(こがねい)）読まれた！？
Did he predict it?!
Touou's got this too.
（日向）桐皇(とうおう)には これもあった…
A defense that combines Momoi's projections and data.
桃井(ももい)の予測と データを
取り入れたディフェンス力…
（日向）ええい…
（若松(わかまつ)）ううっ…
Damn it. Their offense is strong enough...
（木吉）くそ…
攻撃力だけなら まだしも…
Seirin
Touou
Your misdirection trump card has run out of steam too.
（今吉）
切り札のミスディレクションも
効果切れや
Spirit alone won't change anything.
気合いだけじゃ 何も変わらんで
That's not quite right.
（伊月）それは ちょっと違うな
It didn't run out.
切れたんじゃない
切れさせたんだ
We made it run out.
なっ 消えた！
He disappeared!
What?!
（今吉）何やと…！？
He didn't disappear.
（リコ）消えたんじゃない
消したのよ！
He was erased.
（リコ）ミスディレクションが
切れて 初めて使える大技
It's a technique that can only be used
when Kuroko's misdirection runs out.
ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー！
Misdirection Overflow!
That technique likely carries several risks.
（緑間(みどりま)）あの技には おそらく
いくつか リスクがあるのだよ
What Kuroko is doing is like performing
a trick while showing how it's done.
今の黒子は
ネタばらしをしながら—
手品をやっているような
ものなのだよ
In other words,
すなわち この試合が終われば…
桐皇相手に—
once this game ends,
he won't be able to use his
misdirection against Touou again.
ミスディレクションは
もう二度と使えない
（黒子）それでも—
It's still
better than losing here.
ここで負けるよりマシです
Seirin
Touou
He combined it with Kuroko's Overflow!
（若松）黒子のオーバーフローとの
合わせ技か！
It's not that he's fast!
（桜井）速いとか
そういう感覚じゃない！
まるで 時間が飛んだみたいに…
It felt like time just skipped forward!
Seirin
Touou
（青峰(あおみね)）あっ…！
（火神）でえい！
We'll worry about the future when we get there.
（黒子）先のことは
またその時 考えます
（青峰）テツ…
Tetsu...
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: Govna
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: AMS, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Episode
I Believe
（黄瀬(きせ)）決まった！
He made the shot.
They took back the points they lost already.
（笠松(かさまつ)）
すぐさま取り返してきたな
Seirin
Touou
I can't stop him.
（火神）止められねぇ… くそぉっ
Damn it! We're not closing the gap.
差が つまらねぇ！
What should we do?
どうすりゃいいんだ…
どうすりゃあ…
How can we stop him?
（火神）あっ…
（日向）ドンマイ
Don't worry about it. Let's shift gears.
切りかえていくぞ
But...
でも…
You've been able to stay on that monster
as much as you have because of who you are.
オマエだから あのバケモンを
そこまでマークできてたんだ
They can't stop you either.
止められないのは 相手も一緒だ
We'll take
なら こっちは ３点ずつ いくぞ！
three points at a time.
（日向）えいっ！
（桜井）うっ！
A three!
（桜井）スリー！
He's not afraid of missing at all.
（桜井）外すことを
まったく恐れていない
Can he trust his own shots that much?
そこまで自分のシュートを
信じられるものなのか！
Yeah, I believe...
（日向）ああ 信じてるぜ—
仲間をな！
（木吉）くっ！
I believe in my teammates!
I'm not shooting because I won't miss.
（日向）
外さないから 打てるんじゃねぇ
外しても大丈夫だから
打てるんだ！
I'm shooting because it's okay even if I do!
（ホイッスル）
（小金井）入ったぁー！！
He made the shot!
Touou
Seirin
（桜井）ううっ
（日向）ええい
He's been making three after three against me.
（桜井）ボクのところから
立て続けにスリーを決められたんだ
絶対 取り返す！
I'll get those points back!
Go!
（桜井）いっけぇ！
桜井！
Sakurai!
It's no good. His rhythm is off.
（今吉）アカン リズムが悪い！
Getting flustered just because they closed the gap a little...
（青峰）ったく ちょっと
詰められたくらいで—
オタオタしやがって
（青峰）よこせ！
（桜井）ハッ！
Give me the ball!
えいっ！
させるか！
No, you don't!
（火神）なっ 何っ！？
What?!
（木吉）しまった フェイク…！
Crap! It's a fake!
He drew a foul while making the shot, which means...
（観客）ファウルをもらいながら
入ったってことは…
Pushing, white No. 7!
（審判）プッシング 白７番！
Basket counts!
バスケットカウント
ワンスロー！
And one!
It counted.
（日向）バスカン！
（伊月）３点プレー…！
It's a three-point play.
Touou emphasizes individual skill,
（今吉）桐皇は
超個人技重視のチームやが—
but we believe in something too.
ワシらかて
信じてるモンはある
It's
それは…
Aomine's strength.
（今吉）青峰の力や
Seirin
Touou
They're ten points behind again.
（高尾(たかお)）
これでまた 10点差か
ハァ… ハァ…
Kagami, Kiyoshi,
火神君 木吉先輩
do you have a minute?
ちょっといいですか
Seirin
Touou
Damn it! The gap isn't getting smaller!
（降旗(ふりはた)）
くっそ… 差が縮まらない！
What are we supposed to do?
（福田(ふくだ)）
どうすりゃいいんだー！
（黄瀬）これは…
（笠松）トリプルチーム！
They're...
...triple-teaming him.
Seirin's challenging him!
誠凛(せいりん)が勝負に出た！
（緑間）青峰の怖さは
スピードやスキルだけではない
Aomine is not just terrifying because of his speed or skill.
The true nuisance is his overwhelming shooting power
本当にやっかいなのは
そこからの—
どんな体勢からでも決めてくる
圧倒的なシュート力
that allows him to make shots from any position.
野性を身につけた
火神の力をもってしても—
Even Kagami's acquisition of animal instincts hasn't allowed them to stop him.
それを止められたわけではない
While Seirin's offensive power has increased,
誠凛の攻撃力が
上がったところで—
they will never close the gap in a shootout.
点の取り合いでは
決して差はつまらない
If they can't stop Aomine,
青峰を止めなければ
誠凛に勝ち目はない…！
Seirin has no chance of winning.
They're triple-teaming him?
（若松）３人がかりだと！？
Are they for real?
（諏佐(すさ)）マジかよ こいつら！？
パスも出させないつもりか！
They don't even intend to let him pass!
（今吉）青峰の選択肢に
はなからパスはない
Passing isn't an option for Aomine in the first place.
It's the simplest and most effective solution.
一番単純かつ 効果的や…
ただ…
However...
フッ 少なすぎるやろ
それじゃあ
That's not enough.
He's going sideways?!
（木吉）横だと…！？
Kagami, Kiyoshi,
（黒子）火神君 木吉先輩
do you have a minute?
ちょっといいですか
I'll stop Aomine.
青峰君を止めます
力を貸してください
Lend me your strength.
You want to triple-team him?
トリプルチームってことか？
I'm not sure even three of us can stop Aomine as he is now.
だが今の青峰は ３人でも
止められるかどうか…
I know.
分かってます
That's why I want Kagami to let him past at first.
だから火神君には
一度 抜かれてほしいんです
They let him past on purpose!
（桜井）
わざと抜かれたのか！
（若松）これが狙いか！
死角からのブロック！
This is what they were after!
They're blocking from his blind spot!
かわした！
He dodged it!
（青峰）フン！
（桐皇選手）もらったぁー！
He made it!
That's impossible. Aomine...
（今吉）バカな… 青峰が—
あそこから 外すやと…？
He missed from there?!
Tetsu...
テツ… テメエ…！
You bastard.
あ… まさか！？
Could it be?
外させたんか？
Did he make him miss?
あいつが！
Stopping Aomine as he is now is probably impossible.
（黒子）今の青峰君を止めるのは
おそらく不可能です
That's why, when he shoots, I'll draw his attention
away from the hoop for a moment using my Overflow.
だからオーバーフローで
シュートのとき—
一瞬だけリングから
青峰君の意識を外します
That can't be enough.
いや… だが それだけで…
It would probably have hardly any effect on a normal shot.
（黒子）普通のシュートなら
ほとんど効果はないでしょう
However, aiming for the hoop while moving at high speed is a different story.
ただし 高速で動きながら
リングを狙うなら—
話は別です
一瞬の視線のズレも
速ければ速いほど—
The faster he's going, the more effective a moment of distraction will be.
幅は大きくなる
As long as you two push Aomine to the limit...
木吉先輩と火神君が—
青峰君をギリギリまで
追い詰めてくれれば…
I had no idea he could use his Overflow like this.
（今吉）オーバーフローに
こんな使い方があるとは…
味方から自分やなく
リングから自分への視線誘導
He can misdirect his opponent's attention away from the hoop as well.
高速シュートの精度を下げる
ミスディレクション…！
It's a type of misdirection that decreases the accuracy of high-speed shots.
I can't stop you,
（黒子）ボクには青峰君を
止めることはできません けど—
but Seirin will not lose.
誠凛は負けない！
（青峰）フッ
やってくれんじゃねーか テツ！
You've really done it now, Tetsu.
We're six points behind!
（小金井）６点差だぁー！
Don't pull back! Meet them head on!
引くな！ 当たるぞ！
What?!
何やと！？
（諏佐）な…
（若松）ぬあっ！
It's a zone press.
（高尾）ゾーンプレス？
しかも１-２-１-１(ワン ツー ワン ワン)！
And it's 1-2-1-1!
It's a high-level formation that makes steals easy but is weak once broken through.
ボールは奪いやすいが
突破されるともろい 上級陣形…
まさか ここで…！
Why are they doing this now?
This is the only time to do it.
いや むしろ ここしかねぇ！
Seirin can smell the moment of truth.
（笠松）勝負所の嗅覚は
持ってるぜ 誠凛！
Defense! Defense! Defense!
（誠凛部員たち）ディーフェンス！
ディーフェンス！…
ディーフェンス！
Defense! Defense! Defense!
（木吉）ぬうっ！
（若松）ううっ…
This pressure is crazy!
（若松）この圧力 …ヤベェ！
（若松）フン！
ぐわあああ！
ぬああ…！
Pushing, black No. 9!
（審判）プッシング！ 黒９番！
A defensive foul on a three-pointer...
スリーポイントシュート時の
ディフェンスファウル…
フリースロー ３本
Three free throws.
If he makes all of them...
（笠松）全部決めれば…
（黄瀬）３点差…
...it'll be a three point gap.
（選手たち）よっしゃあー！
All right!
Yeah!
Hey, Ryo.
（青峰）おい 良(りょう)！
（桜井）ああっ…
はいっ！ あの…
すいません！ すいません！！
Yes!
Uh, I'm sorry! Sorry!
（青峰）ちょうどいいわ
このあと リバウンド 代われ
Good timing.
Switch to rebounding after this.
Aomine's not part of the setup?
（火神）
青峰がセットから外れた…？
How long has it been
（青峰）いつからだろう…
since I started yawning as I left home on days I had games?
試合の日の朝 あくびしながら
家を出るようになったのは
Touou
Since when did I stop feeling anything when I won?
いつからだろう…
Touou
勝っても 何も感じなくなったのは
I just wanted an opponent I could face with everything I had.
ただオレは—
すべてを ぶつけさせてくれる
相手が欲しかった
Touou
ずっと望んでいた
I've been longing for one.
Touou
A game so close I'm not sure if I'll win or lose.
勝つか負けるか分からない
ギリギリのクロスゲーム
Touou
Thanks, Tetsu.
（青峰）感謝するぜ テツ
Seirin
Touou
He made all three!
（小金井）３本とも決まったー！
We're three points behind! Three points!
（福田）３点差！ ３点差だー！
No way...
そんな…
That's impossible.
（黄瀬）あり得ない…！
ゾーンに—
Did he
enter the Zone?
入ったというのか？
（ナレーション）“ゾーン”—
The Zone.
In this state of extreme focus,
all unnecessary thoughts disappear
余計な思考 感情が
すべてなくなり—
and the athlete becomes entirely absorbed in his play.
プレーに没頭する
極限の集中状態…
練習に練習を重ねた者だけが—
Only those who have practiced and practiced
earn the right to stand before the door,
その扉の前に
立つことを許され—
それでもなお 気まぐれにしか
開くことはない
and it only opens unpredictably.
It is the ultimate domain, and opens only to the chosen.
それは 選ばれた者しか
入れない—
究極の領域
However, Aomine's senses almost mockingly force the door open on their own.
だが… 青峰のセンスは—
それをあざ笑うかのように
扉を自力で こじあける
We've never seen this before either.
（紫原(むらさきばら)）オレらも 初めて見る
This is
（赤司(あかし)）これが—
Aomine's true form.
青峰の本当の姿！
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Crap! He's reacting so fast!
（日向）やべぇっ！
なんて反応の速さだ！
This isn't even funny.
冗談きついぜ…
バケモンだ…！
He's a monster!
Normally it is impossible to play at 100% of your potential during a game.
本来 試合で実力の100％を
発揮するのは不可能だ
どんなに集中した一流選手でも
80％が限界
Even a highly focused top-tier player reaches his limit at 80%.
However, being in the Zone makes that impossible 100% a possibility.
だがゾーンは その不可能なはずの
100％を 可能にする
Furthermore, Aomine's 100% is a total unknown.
しかも あの青峰の100％なら
完全に未知の領域
He seems twice as fast as usual.
体感的には おそらく
今までの倍は速い
Ridiculous.
バカな… ２人がほとんど
反応すらできないのか…
The two of them could hardly respond at all.
Seirin
Touou
Don't give up!
Seirin
Touou
（日向）諦めるな！ あと５分だ！
Seirin
Touou
There are five more minutes!
Seirin
Touou
We'll hang on, even if it kills us!
死んでも食らいつくぞ！
（木吉）ぐっ… ああっ ていっ…
フン！
They're amazing!
すごいぞ みんな！
They're still determined!
（河原(かわはら)）まだ気迫 十分だ！
We knew from the beginning they wouldn't give up now.
（今吉）分かっとるで
はなから ここまできて
諦めるタマやないやろ
Even so...
ただなぁ それでも…！
Good.
いいねぇ
そうこなくっちゃよ！
That's how it should be!
Aomine is the strongest!
（観客たちの歓声）
（今吉）最強は 青峰や！
ハァ… ハァ…
His Overflow isn't reducing the accuracy of those shots anymore.
オーバーフローを使った
シュート精度ダウンも—
効かなくなってる
もう青峰を止める
術(すべ)はない…
He doesn't have anything left to stop Aomine.
Seirin
Touou
Senpai, I need a favor.
（火神）先輩 ちょっと頼みが
Huh?
青峰とサシでやらせてくれ… です
Let me go
one-on-one with Aomine, sir.
One-on-one?
（小金井）サシで！？
３人がかりでも止められない
バケモノだぞ
Three of you couldn't stop that monster.
Do you have some kind of plan?
なんか 勝算あんの？
No.
いや… ないっス
But I'll do it.
けど… やる！
I have no intention of beating the Generation of Miracles alone now.
いまさら“キセキの世代”
相手に—
１人で勝とうなんて
つもりはないし—
If it'd help the team win, I'd happily sit on the bench.
もしそれがチームの勝利のためなら
喜んでベンチにだって入る
それでも
あいつだけは—
But I have to face him alone.
オレが１人で
やらなきゃダメなんだ
I'll never find what I'm looking for.
（青峰）オレの欲しいもんは
絶対 見つかんねえ
The only one who can beat me is me.
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
Fine.
（日向）分かった
（火神）あ！
You have two minutes.
２分やる エースはオマエだ
好きにやれ
You're the ace.
Do what you want.
キャプテン
Captain...
In the meantime, we'll go at them with everything we have.
（日向）その間はオレらが
全力で食らいつく
It's all on you, Kagami.
託すぜ 火神！
Aomine and Kagami...
青峰と火神の…
ワンオンワン！？
They're going one-on-one?
（今吉）ここにきて
エースに託すかぁ
They're leaving it up to their ace now?
けど 正気の沙汰とは思えんで
They don't seem out of their minds though.
Are you trying to prove yourself my equal?
オレとタメはるつもりかよ？
You can't do it.
けど オマエにゃ 無理だ
言ったろう
I told you.
Your light is too dim!
オマエの光じゃ 淡すぎだってよ！
ぐうう！
（ホイッスル）
（観客）決まったー！
He made it!
It's no use.
ダメだな まるで歯が立たない
He's useless against him.
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
More...
（火神）もっと… もっとだ
More!
We won't lose.
（日向）負けるか！
絶対取り返すぞ！
Let's take it back!
Misdirection Overflow!
（２人）ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー！
（伊月）
うっ… タイミングがズレた…
Our timing was off?!
No! The Overflow's effectiveness is starting to run out!
違う！ オーバーフローの効力が
切れ始めたんだ！
Crap! If the ball goes out now...
（日向）ヤベェ！
ここでボールが出たら…
まだだ！！
It's not over yet!
フンッ！
何っ！？
What?!
黒子君！
Kuroko!
（木吉）日向！
Hyuga!
I can't let you pull away now.
（黒子）ここで離されるわけには
いきません
An ace carrying his teammates' wishes cannot lose.
みんなの想いを背負ったエースは
絶対に負けない
信じてますから
火神君を
I believe in Kagami.
Defense! Defense! Defense!
（誠凛部員たち）ディーフェンス！
ディーフェンス…
ディーフェンス！
Defense! Defense! Defense!
Damn it!
（火神）くそっ！
Seirin
Touou
Damn it, why?
（火神）くそぉっ 何でだよ
Why am I so weak?
何でオレはこんなに… 弱(よえ)えんだ！
We have to win.
絶対に勝つんだ！
I don't want to lose anymore.
嫌なんだよ… もう負けるのは
I don't want it
嫌なんだよ こんなとこで
終わっちまうのは
to end here.
I'm sick of it.
嫌なんだよ もう…
I'm
sick of seeing my friends cry!
泣いてる仲間を見るのは…！
ここでやらなきゃ
いつやるんだよ！！
If I can't do it now,
when will I do it?!
What?
何っ！？
（今吉）あり得へん…
There's no way.
He reacted to Aomine in the Zone?
ゾーンに入った青峰に
反応したやと…？
That's not...
そんなことが…
No way...
（リコ）まさか… 火神君も！？
Did Kagami also...
I take back what I said, Kagami.
（青峰）前言撤回するぜ 火神
You're the best!
サイコーだな オマエ…！！
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
Kagami entered the Zone too.
（黒子）火神君もゾーンに
（さつき）
ゾーン同士の戦いになるなんて…
I can't believe this turned into a battle of two players in the Zone.
Since this summer's loss, we've risen back up.
（黒子）夏の敗北から ボクたちは
はい上がってきました
（さつき）テツ君…
Tetsu...
I believe in Kagami.
（黒子）ボクは信じています
火神君を—
Episode
I Won't Lose
誠凛の勝利を！
I believe in Seirin's victory!